

PERSONAL

- Name MYKHAILO GAMALIA
- Address Kyiv
- Phone number +380 67 447 99 79
- Email mykhailo.gamalia@gmail.com
- EinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/ mykhailo-gamalia-22b074b5/

INTERESTS

- Cycling
- Bowling
- Billiards

LANGUAGES

English Ukrainian Russian



MYKHAILO GAMALIA

Data Analyst / Data Scientist

I am a math and computer science teacher by education, and I worked in a school for 4 years. However, my professional career has been mainly in the toy industry.

I have experience working as a product specialist, a manager of foreign economic activity, and a category manager.

But for the past 10 years, my primary activity has been as a data analyst.

I create and maintain complex analytics for the company. A comprehensive data model was created using Power Pivot in MS Excel and MS Power BI. This model allows you to analyze, support and forecast the operation of chain stores according to all the main indicators.

For the past 6 months, I studied and mastered the specialty of Data Science, which gave me the opportunity to discover new tools and areas of data analysis.

At the moment, I am engaged in the creation of machine learning models for forecasting the main indicators of network performance using Python.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Jul 2012 - May 2023

DATA ANALYST IN RETAIL TRADE

PLANETTOYS LLC, Kyiv

- A data analyst specialist in PLANETTOYS chain of stores
- · Category manager LEGO constructors
- · Participation in foreign exhibitions and presentations
- · Compilation of analytical reports
- Creation and maintenance of a complex analytics system in MS Excel and Power BI
- Creation and maintenance of the product directory
- Analysis and forecasting of the main indicators

Jun 2008 - Jun 2012

Manager of Foreign Economic Activity

PLANETTOYS LLC, Kyiv

- Work with foreign partners
- Sale and service of products
- · Brand manager
- Participation in foreign exhibitions and presentations

Feb 2003 - Jan 2005

Deputy director

L-Toys LLC, Kyiv

- · cooperation with the LEGO company
- · ordering goods from the manufacturer
- preparation of documents for customs clearance
- sale and support of LEGO products in Ukraine

Nov 1998 - Jun 2008

Manager / commodity expert

"Budynok Igrashok" shop network, Kyiv

- · Order / Product accounting
- Ordering goods from suppliers
- Processing invoices
- Sales analysis
- Creation of analytical reports

Aug 1997 - Aug 2001

Teacher of Mathematics and Computer Science

Muzychi secondary school, Kyiv reg.

- · teaching mathematics
- teaching physics
- · teaching informatics



EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Sep 1992 - Jun 1997 Teacher of Mathematics, Computer Science, and **Computing Technology** National Pedagogical Dragomanov University, Kyiv **Python for Data Science** Sep 2022 - Apr 2023 STARTUP IT Academy, Kyiv Jan 2023 - May 2023 IT English / B2 Study Space, Kyiv SQL for business analysis Nov 2021 - May 2022 DATA BI, Kyiv **MS Excel Advanced** Apr 2020 - Jun 2020 DATA BI, Kyiv Feb 2020 - Apr 2020 MS Excel: business analysis and forecasting DATA BI, Kyiv Sep 2006 - Dec 2007 English language course / Advanced American English Center, Kyiv



SKILLS

MS Excel	****
Microsoft Power BI	****
Data modeling with Power Pivot and Power BI	****
Data Analysis	****
Data Manipulation	****
Data Visualization	****
SQL	****
Python	****
Pandas / Seaborn / NumPy	****
GitHub	****
Jupyter notebook / Google colaboratory	****